2011年秋天  莉莉和马修收到
In the fall of 2011, Lily and Marshall received
一份莉莉祖父母送的惊喜大礼
a surprising gift from Lily's grandparents:
一座长岛的房子
their house in Long Island.
莉莉和马修因为一个简单的理由
Lily and Marshall decided to sell it
决定将其出售
for one simple reason.
那可是在长岛啊
It's Long Island.
我可不想在长岛度周六
I don't want to spend my Saturday in Long Island.
我知道  宝贝
I know, babe,
但是中介在房子里布置了些道具家具
but the realtor staged the place with fake furniture
她想在开售前  让我们去看看
and she wants us to check it out before the open house.
好吧
All right.
至少我们能在道具床上做爱吧
Can we at least do it on the fake bed?
这种求欢的事还是我来吧
I'm embarrassed that you have to ask.
于是他们出发去了长岛
So, they headed out to Long Island,
当他们一推开那扇门...
and when they walked in the door...
我们买了
We'll take it!
我们不能买
We-We can't take it.
我们就是卖方
We're the ones selling it.
我们是要卖房 对吧
We are selling it, right?
宝贝  你的祖父母把这房子彻底交给你了
Baby, your grandparents gave you this house outright.
在我看来  我们有五个选择
So, the way I see it, we have five options.
第一  卖掉它
1, sell it.
第二  空着它  变鬼屋
2, year-round haunted house.
第三  在周围竖起大栅栏  建个猩猩保护区
3, giant fence around the perimeter, chimp sanctuary.
反正后院已经有轮胎秋千了
There's already a tire swing in the backyard.
第四  用锤子凿了它
4, we destroy it with sledgehammers.
我喜欢第四个
I like four.
第五  我们搬进来  抚养孩子长大
5, we move in, raise our children
把这里变成我们的家
and make this our family home.
直到他们毕业
Till they graduate.
然后我们再用锤子凿了它
Then we destroy it with sledgehammers.
全家齐上阵
As a family.
不  不能这么想
No, this is crazy!
我们可是纽约人
We are New York people.
我们有心爱的公寓  它又大又漂亮
We have a big, beautiful apartment that we love.
你说得对
You're right.
但那天  马修和莉莉发生了点状况
But something happened to Lily and Marshall that day.
所有从外地返回纽约家中的
Something that happens to all New Yorkers
纽约人都会遇到这种状况
who return home from anywhere other than New York.
他们又大又温馨的公寓
Their big, lovely apartment...
哟  真是奇了怪了
Huh. That's weird.
瞬间缩水
...shrank.
好吧  感恩节一过  我就节食
Okay, after Thanksgiving, I'm cutting out carbs.
YYeTs人人影视字幕组出品
更多原创字幕翻译 请登陆www.YYeTs.com
时间轴： godwuwen 孤帆  字幕总监： YY
翻译： Vero  非燕  阿蘅阿蘅  一块二  猫中之王 孤帆  字幕总监： YY
校对： YY    后期： 孤帆  字幕总监： YY
老爸老妈浪漫史
第七季  第十一集
孩子们  在过去的几周  巴尼过得很不易
Now, kids, it had been a rough couple weeks for Barney.
他先是背着女友  跟罗宾偷情
First, he cheated on his girlfriend with Robin,
接着为了罗宾  跟女友分手
then he broke up with his girlfriend for Robin,
最后罗宾选择了凯文  放弃了他
then Robin chose Kevin over him.
所以他有点萎靡不振
So he was kind of in a bad place.
你还好吧
You all right?
为什么会不好
Why wouldn't I be all right?
巴尼恢复单身啦
Barney's single again!
美国总算盼到这一天了
It's what America's been clamoring for.
你刚刚结束一段恋情
You just went through a break-up.
人们通常会在这时候做傻事
That's usually when people do something crazy.
如果是个女孩  她就会减掉刘海
If you were a girl, you'd have cut bangs
然后跟你这样的人约会
and be dating you by now.
向我保证  你不会去做傻事
Just promise me you won't do something crazy.
我保证不会做傻事
I promise I won't do something crazy.
别担心  他很快就会做傻事
Don't worry, he's gonna do something crazy.
其实  我觉得我受够女人了
In fact, I think I'm done with girls.
我甚至不确定是否还喜欢她们
I'm not sure I even like them anymore.
鉴于你多年来对她们的所作所为
Based on all the stuff you've done to them over the years,
我不确定你是否喜欢过她们
I'm not sure you ever liked them.
我是说真的
I'm serious.
拜托  你爱死女人了
Come on, you love girls.
如果真要说谁受够女人了  那也应该是我
If anyone should be done with girls, it's me.
瞧瞧我这一年过得
Look at the year I've had.
苏伊  维多利亚  淫荡南瓜妹
Zoey, Victoria, the Slutty Pumpkin.
现在换我担心你会做傻事了
Now I'm worried you're gonna do something crazy.
我可不会做傻事
I'm not gonna do something crazy.
没错  我也离做傻事不远了
And yes, I'm gonna do someththg crazy, too.
但是女人啊
But girls, man.
女人啊
Girls.
-你知道最绝的一招是什么吗  -变成同志
- You know what would kick ass? - Being gay?
变成同志最牛逼了
Being gay would kick ass!
同意  男人之间互相理解
Word. Guys understand each other.
想象有这么一段关系
Imagine a relationship where,
不必每时每刻表达爱意
instead of talking about feelings all the time,
俩人一起只是打电动吃披萨
you just play some Madden, eat a pizza,
一起嗑药  一起嗨
give each other a happy, roll over
更不用抱着一起睡
and have some cuddle-free shut-eye.
哥们儿  不管怎样我要说
Bro, for what it's worth,
如果我们都是同志  你会是我的首选伴侣
if we were both gay, you'd be my first call.
那你介意打给马修  告诉他这话吗
Would you mind calling Marshall and telling him that?
因为他一直以为...
'Cause he thinks...
不行  我只是说假如
No, this is only in a scenario
你和我是同志  与马修无关
where just you and I are gay, not Marshall.
但如果我们三个都是同志
But if all three of us were gay,
你还是会选我  而不是马修  对吧
you'd pick me over Marshall, right?
如果我们三个都是同志
If all three of us were gay?
姐妹  我们仨一定会爽翻天的
Girlfriend, we would all three of us have some fun.
我们绝对会的
Damn right we would.
我们不是同志
We're not gay.
没错  女人才是我的菜
Nope. Stuck with girls.
我真希望男人可以
I wish men could have children
自己生孩子  就像海马一样
on their own, like sea horses.
你这话不会是我以为的那种意思吧
Are you saying what I think you're saying?
他们育儿袋太小了
They have a little pouch.
它们该叫海袋鼠
They should be called sea kangaroos.
不对  你想要孩子吗
No, y-you want kids?
或许我最近是开始有点考虑
Maybe I've kind of lately been thinking
娶妻生子之类的事
about the whole wife and kids thing.
只是娶妻这一环省了
Just minus the wife.
男人也可以把孩子拉扯大
You could always go it alone.
就像《细路仔》里的杜蒙德先生
Like Mr. Drummond on Diff'rent Strokes.
美国80年代电视剧  杜蒙德一人抚养三个孩子
是啊  可那是在80年代
Yeah, but that was the '80s,
那时你还能坐着豪车  随便路过城里任一球场
when you could just swing by any inner-city playground in your limo
接俩孩子回家养呢
and scoop up some kids.
更方便快捷
Simpler times.
我想抚养孩子这种事  还是得个帮手好
I guess it's better to have someone in it with you anyway, you know?
比如终身伴侣
Lifetime partnership.
我生命中唯一
The only partnership in my life
经得起时间考验的伴侣关系就是
that has stood the test of time is this one.
神圣的兄弟情谊
The sacred bond of man and bro.
或许我们该一起组建家庭
Maybe we should start a family together.
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
这地方大得很
This place is huge.
瞧  我还能大摇大摆地跳舞呢
I mean, look, I can dance all crazy in here.
靠...
Oh! Sh...
听着  罗宾
Listen, um, Robin,
你同意今年感恩节都在东梅多过吗
are you okay with us all doing Thanksgiving out in East Meadow?
东梅多是长岛的一个村庄
好呀  应该会好玩吧
Uh, yeah, I guess that'd be nice.
太好了
Oh, great!
我和莉莉打算感恩节过后
And then after Thanksgiving, Lily and I were thinking
在那房子住一段时间
that we would just stay at the house
住到...
until, you know...
终老
we die.
什么
What?
不行
No!
你们不能搬去长岛
You can't move to Long Island!
可房子那么漂亮
But this house is so nice.
宽敞又整洁
It's big, and it's clean,
如果有蟑螂
and if there's cockroaches,
看到我们也会谦虚低头绕路走
they respect us enough to sneak around.
瞧瞧你说那话儿
Listen to yourself.
这全是孕期犯傻症在作祟
This is Pregnancy Brain all over again.
不  我的犯傻期已经过了
No, I'm done with Pregnancy Brain.
现在是奇幻春梦期
I've moved on to weird pregnancy sex dreams.
孕期妇女会在孕中期性欲大增  而且睡觉时容易做梦
长官好
Officer.
你懂的  你懂的
You know. You know.
我只是说  你们现在脑子不清楚
I'm-I'm just saying, you're not in the right mind
不适宜做重大决定
to be making this decision right now.
罗宾说得对
You know what? Robin's right.
我们现在的状态的确不适宜做重大决定
We are in no state of mind to make this kind of decision.
谢谢  世界终于恢复正常了
Thank you. And now you're stepping off the crazy bus.
我们让老天爷做主吧
We let the universe decide.
世界又开始疯狂了
And now you're back on board.
听到了吗  老天爷
You hear that, Universe?
如果你在接下来的24小时内
If you send us a sign in the next...
给我们指示
24 hours,
我们就搬去长岛  说好咯
then we're moving to Long Island! Okay?
计时开始
Go.
伙计们
Hey, guys,
我再说最后一次  这地方大得很
for the last time, this place is enormous--
烦死了  你们家到底有多少盏灯啊
Geez, how many lamps do you have?
这想法太妙了
It's genius!
与其将人生浪费在某个女人身上
Instead of throwing away your life marrying some girl,
还不如和你的铁哥们儿一起养个孩子呢
you just go splitsies on a kid with your best bro!
我不必纠结于选择
I wouldn't have to choose
约会还是成家
between dating and having a family.
因为我可以带孩子去约会
Hell, I could bring the kids on dates!
家庭破碎
And a broken home?
那是什么
Um, what's that?
我们的孩子绝不会知道
Our kids will never know,
因为我们永远不会分开
'cause we're never gonna split up!
为什么要分开
Why would we?
当然  如果被孩子她妈撞见
I mean, sure, when your wife walks in
你和火辣空姐的好事  她铁定跟你离婚
on you banging a hot flight attendant, you get a divorce.
但如果是被孩子他爹撞见了
But when your bro-parent walks in on you
结果就太不同啦
banging a hot flight attendant...
应该为这种家庭击掌欢呼
You get five of these bad boys, right up high!
毫不犹豫加入同欢  对吧
And you totally join in, right?!
-不行  这是底线  -这是底线
- Oh, no, there's the line. - That's the line.
我们要有分寸  还好我们知道底线在哪儿
We found the line. It's good we know where it is.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
我们有事宣布
We have an announcement.
所以你们的意思是
So what you're saying is,
如果你们注定要搬去长岛
if you're meant to move to Long Island,
那么上天的指示
some sign from the universe
就会奇迹般地出现在你家门前吗
will magically appear at your doorstep?
孩子们
Now, kids,
罗宾话音刚落那一刻  其实没人敲门
I don't think there was a knock on the door at that exact moment,
但为了凸显故事效果...
but for the purposes of this story...
你好  我是克莱夫
Hi, I'm Clive.
我就住在你们楼上
I live upstairs from you.
这是你们的牌子吗["牌子"与"指示"同音]
Is this your sign?
房屋待售
我不清楚  克莱夫
I don't know, Clive.
是吗
Is it?
我们把这牌子忘外面了吗
Oh, did we leave that outside?
对  我们准备卖掉我们在长岛的房子
Yeah, we're selling our house in Long Island.
可惜你们卖的不是这里
Oh. Too bad you're not selling this place.
我想把我家改造成复式公寓呢
I'd love to turn mine into a duplex.
而且我愿意出高价
And I'd give you a really good price for it,
因为我富得流油
because I am so rich.
这句他可没说
He did not say that.
看鞋子就知道了
His shoes did.
好吧  重点是我们收到上天的指示了
Okay, the point is, we got the sign.
我们要搬去东梅多咯
We're moving to East Meadow.
咱们去拿点香槟吧
Let's get some champagne.
就这样  莉莉和马修
And just like that, Lily and Marshall
即将开启他们人生的新篇章
were beginning a new chapter in their lives.
这让我们别无选择  唯有...
Which meant only one thing for us...
抱个孩子回家养吧
We're having a baby!
"一个孩子两个爹"计划启动
Bro-parents activate!
-我们讨论一下孩子的名字吧  -巴尼
- Hey, let's talk baby names! - Barney...
天啊  这名字也是我的首选
Oh, my God! That was my first choice, too.
不  听着  咱俩都喝醉了
No, listen. You and I are drunk.
所以说  就算真有机会收养孩子
Which means there's a chance that adopting a baby--
不管我现在把他想得多可爱
no matter how cute he is in my head
穿着小牛仔装  像骑马一样
with his little cowboy outfit on and he's riding our dog
骑着我们的狗  对  还要养条狗
like a horse and we also have a dog,
纯种金毛  孩子骑着安全  因为这狗会救人
purebred Golden, but it's okay, she's a rescue--
金毛常被训练为救援犬
这可能不是个好主意
might not be a good idea.
没错
You're right.
那我们就各自回家  吃片阿司匹林
So let's go home, take some aspirin,
多喝点水[醒酒]
drink lots of water,
看看明天  是否还觉得这是个好主意
and then see if it's still a good idea tomorrow.
仍然是一个好主意
It's still a good idea!
绝对是个好主意
It's totally still a good idea!
抱个孩子回家养吧
We're having a baby!
孩子们  不得不强调一下
Kids, I cannot stress this enough:
当时我们处于"王老五变二百五"的艰难时期
Barney and I were going through a tough time.
你们不准搬  就这么说定了
You're not leaving, and that's final.
瞧瞧我凌晨四点在纽约买到了什么
Look what I bought at 4:00 a.M. In New York City.
一盒超级流行的韩国电影走私录影带
A bootleg VHS of a very, very popular Korean movie,
一个路一·威等的正品提包
this genuine Lenny Vintone purse
Lenny Vintone名称缩写也为LV
一个能贩卖肾脏的男人的电话号码
and the number of a man who can get me a kidney.
在长岛能搞到这些吗
Do that on Long Island.
罗宾  我们很感激你的大力挽留
Look, Robin, we appreciate that you want us to stay in the city,
但是我们已经决定了
but this is what we want.
你懂我们的  对不
I mean, you understand, right?
不懂
No.
长岛有几怪
Here are a few fun facts about Long Island.
第一怪  布鲁克林的屁通通吹到长岛
Number one: it's Brooklyn's fart trail..
不得不再次强调  巴尼和我
So Barney and I-- and again, going through a tough time,
当时正处于艰难时期
can't stress that enough--
我们找到一个领养机构的网站
found an adoption agency Web site
并填写在线申请书
and filled out their online application.
名字  巴尼·斯丁森
Name Barney Stinson.
泰德·莫斯比
Ted Mosby.
地址
Address...
写我的地址  韦斯切斯特
Oh, put my address in Westchester.
他们更愿意看到
They'll want to see we'll be
孩子在一个良好的环境中长大
raising this child in a good environment.
就是  乡下
You know, the suburbs.
什么   不要
What? No.
-我的人都在这里  -你的人
- All my guys are here. - Your guys?
对啊  我所有事情都交给他们代办
Yeah. You know how I got a guy for everything?
他们全在纽约
Well, they're all in New York.
做西服的  做皮鞋的  买票的  泡吧的
My suit guy, my shoe guy, my ticket guy, my club guy.
如果我没人可用了
And if I don't have a guy for something,
我还有专员帮我找人来用
then I have a guy guy to get me a guy.
说来稀奇  那个人就叫"专员"
And oddly enough, his name is Guy.
好吧  这样如何
Okay, fine. How about this?
周一至周五我们待在城里
We stay in the city during the week,
一到周末  我们就去郊外骑马
then on the weekend, country house in the burbs!
-这就是一个孩子两个爹的好处  -正是
- This is why bro-parenting works! - Totally!
你的工资再加上我的工资
And with your salary plus my salary,
我们完全可以供两套房子
we can totally afford two places.
怎么了
What?
难道你...还打算继续上班
So... uh, you're gonna keep your job?
罗宾  讨论到此为止吧
Robin, this discussion is closed.
这是上天的指示  所以我们听命接旨
The universe told us to do it, so we're doing it.
老天爷也会有失算的时候
Well, the universe gets it wrong sometimes.
还记得马修在环境律师
Remember when Marshall was trying to decide between
和银行职员之间犹豫不决的那事吗
becoming an environmental lawyer and working at a bank?
这是个有趣的故事
That's a funny story.
马修厌倦了在巨人国家银行上班
Marshall was fed up with his job at GNB and was
考虑着要不要狠下心来辞职
thinking about leaving it all behind,
所以他和莉莉一致同意
so he and Lily agreed he should wait for a sign
等待上天的指示
from the universe to tell him what to do.
于是某天
Then one day...
以下场景皆出自《捉鬼敢死队》
救护车
待售
果然
Of course.
天意啊
It's so clear.
原来答案就在眼前
It's been right there all along.
我要打给莉莉
I have to call Lily.
抱歉  打扰了先生
Excuse me. Excuse me, sir.
抱歉  我能借你的...
I'm sorry, but, um, can I please borrow your...
-欧尼·哈德逊  -正是在下
- Ernie Hudson? - Yes.
欧尼·哈德逊曾主演电影《追鬼敢死队》
能借你的电话一用吗
Can I borrow your phone?
你要打给谁
Who you gonna call?
那马修有变成捉鬼敢死队的队员吗
And did Marshall become a Ghostbuster?
消防站那房子至今没卖出去
That firehouse is still for sale.
连欧尼·哈德逊都求你不要加入
Even Ernie Hudson begged you not to go through with that.
欧尼·哈德逊是个懦夫
Ernie Hudson is a coward!
我当然要继续工作啦
Of course I'm gonna keep my job.
我为什么要辞职
Why wouldn't I keep my job?
我的意思是  建筑对你来说...
Well, I mean, this whole architecture thing...
爱好多过工作吧
isn't it more of a hobby?
什么
Excuse me?
好  开始吵架了  算了
And now we're fighting. You know what?
忘记我刚说的话
Forget I said anything.
不不不  我们还没讨论完呢
No! No, no, no. We're having this discussion.
建筑是我终生的事业
Architecture is my life's work.
你为什么不辞职呢
Why don't you quit your job?
我都不知道你靠什么谋生
I don't even know what it is you do for a living.
"我靠什么谋生"
"What it is I do for a living?"
当然是工作了  泰德
I work, Ted, 14 hours a day
当你坐在那儿信手涂鸦时
so that our baby can have food
老子一天上十四个小时班
and clothes and a nice house,
我们的孩子才有得吃  有得穿  有得住
while you sit around doodling pictures of buildings.
这就是我谋生的方法
That's "What it is I do."
我现在不想讨论了  老子要去酒吧
You know what? Screw this. I'm gonna go to the bar.
去吧  去吧  你以为灌醉自己
Yeah, right, right, 'cause the answer's always
就能解决问题吗
at the bottom of a bottle!
等等  站住
Wait, wait, wait! Hold it!
多动脑子勿动气  快动脑
Brainstorm. Brainstorm.
谁都不用辞职
Nobody quits their job.
我们找一个保姆
We get a nanny.
保姆归我
Dibs on the nanny.
不  不准勾搭保姆
No. No banging the nanny.
泰德  请不要现在就开始制定
Ted, please don not dig in on this whole
"不准上保姆"这种硬性规定
no-banging-the-nanny policy.
好吧  那我们找两个保姆
Okay, fine. We'll get two nannies.
一个用来滚床单  一个用来看孩子
One for banging, one for childcare.
兼滚床单  俩保姆都归我
Slash banging. Dibs on both nannies!
想象一下  泰德  你和我
Just think of it, Ted, you and me,
一起生活  有个孩子
living together, with our kid,
-两个热辣的保姆  一条宠物眼镜蛇   -什么
- my two hot nannies, our pet cobra... - What?
孩子需要一只宠物眼镜蛇  泰德
A kid needs a pet cobra, Ted.
少啰嗦
Don't be a pill about this.
欢乐派对连连开  个个开足一整周
And we'll have amazing weeklong parties,
满屋子都是刀剑和忍者飞镖
and there'll be swords and ninja stars lying around.
那一刻我终于明白
That's when I realized:
和朋友一起领养个孩子  是疯狂
adopting a baby with a friend? Crazy.
和巴尼一起领养个孩子  是真他妈疯狂
Adopting a baby with Barney? Freaking nuts.
我不能和你一起领养孩子  巴尼
I can't adopt a baby with you, Barney.
为什么不能
Why not?
因为孩子还没领进家
Because we don't even have one yet
你就表现得像个差劲的父亲
and you're already a terrible father.
我懂了
Oh, I get it.
你肯定是想上保姆
You want one of the nannies.
门儿都没有  两个都是我的
Well, you can't have 'em! They're mine!
所以麻烦你另请一个保姆吧
So you're just gonna have to get yourself a third nanny.
对了  第三个也归我  祝您愉快
Except dibs on the third nanny! Good day!
话说感恩节将近
Which brings us to Thanksgiving.
马修  莉莉和罗宾出发
Marshall, Lily and Robin were heading out
去长岛做准备
to Long Island early to get ready.
好吧  这怎么可能出得去
Okay, how is this even possible?!
这就跟生孩子一样 费死劲儿了
'Cause how did we even get it in here?!
看到你这个大孩子  我坚决要换成无痛分娩
Okay, I change my mind. I want an epidural.
你们都疯了吧
You guys are crazy.
这个地方大得很
This place is enormous.
环顾四周
I mean, look arou...
你他妈的没听过有个东西叫吊灯啊
Have you never heard of overhead lighting?!
你说的没错
You're right.
我懂了
I get it.
这个地方太棒了
This place is great.
问一下  洗手间在哪里
Um, excuse me. Where is the restroom?
-就在那  -太好了
- Oh. Right there. - Oh, good, great.
我要进去
I'm just gonna go in there and...
除非你俩答应我不搬家  否则我就他妈的不出来
not come out until you promise never to move away!
还好我们有三个洗手间
It's a good thing we have three bathrooms.
巴尼
Hey, Barney.
那天我说你是个糟糕的父亲
Uh, listen, sorry about the other day
我对此深感抱歉
when I said you'd be a terrible father.
你这么想很正常
You had no reason to think otherwise.
完全可以理解  我没生气
Totally understandable. I'm not mad.
谢谢  说实话
Thanks. And, uh, let's be honest,
那天我们都有点疯狂
we were both acting a little crazy.
我觉得我们俩都没准备好承担责任...
I don't think either of us is truly ready for the responsibility of...
爸爸回来咯
Daddy's home.
巴尼  这宝宝从哪儿弄来的
Uh, Barney, uh, where did you get this baby?
拜托
Please.
是你领养的吗
Did you adopt it?
拜托
Please.
你有个能帮你弄到小孩的人吗
Do you have a baby guy?
是不是找"专员"这个专员  帮你找了个能弄到小孩的人
Did Guy the guy guy get you a baby guy?
泰德  我们得走了
Ted, we should get going.
不不不  我哪都不跟你去
No, no, no. I'm not going anywhere with you.
从目前情况看
For all I know,
我很有可能在协助及唆使绑架
I could be aiding and abetting a kidnapping.
爸比没有在生气
Sh...bro-ddy's not mad.
他只是讲话有点点大声
He's just being a wittle loud.
他可耐你了  真的哦
He wuvs you! Yes, he does!
-疯了疯了  -我们在外面等你
- This is insane! - We'll be waiting outside.
-快点  -不行  我做不到
- Come on. - No, I can't.
听不到听不到
Yeah. Na-na-na.
但我们还是出门了
But then we went outside.
我的天
Oh, my goodness.
-好漂亮的宝宝哦  -谢谢
- What a beautiful baby. - Thank you.
顺便说一下  我和我朋友不是一对
By the way, my friend and I, we're not a couple.
我们只是共同抚养孩子的
We are two straight guys who are single
两个单身直男  别误会哦
and we have a baby. Just so you know.
好可爱的小姑娘哦
Look at this sweet girl.
我刚刚跟这个女生说过
Hi. I was just telling this first girl,
我和我朋友  都是直男
my friend and I, both straight,
都是单身  小孩也有了
both available, and we have a baby.
这个小天使是谁呀
Oh, who is this little angel?
好吧  再简单说遍  我和他
Okay, real quick: me and him,
直男  单身  有小孩
not gay, single, have a baby.
我们应该做个告示牌
We should look into having a sign made.
孩子们  再次强调  当时日子真心艰难呀
Kids, again, we were going through a difficult time.
不过这部分还是挺开心的
But this part was kind of fun.
好可爱哦
Aw...! So cute!
妙  太妙了
This is awesome.
对不对
Right?
罗宾  出来咱们谈谈吧
Robin, come out and talk to us.
除非这世界停止疯狂
I'm not coming out of this bathroom
否则我就他妈的不出来
until everyone stops acting crazy!
这世界很正常
No one is being crazy.
再次强调  我是为了凸显故事效果...
Again, for the purposes of this story...
泰德和我有小孩了  很疯狂吧
Ted and I have a baby. Crazy!
到底怎么回事
What the hell is that?
各位  她叫小旋风·史丁森·莫斯比
Guys, this is Hurricane Stinson-Mosby.
是莫斯比·史丁森
Mosby-Stinson.
你为孩子取名叫"小旋风"
You named your baby Hurricane?
真是
That is...
太不为宝宝的未来考虑了
ultimately inconsiderate to the child
这名字可要跟着她一辈子呀
who has to live with that name.
巴尼怎么把小孩弄到手的
Okay, how the hell does Barney have a baby?
不知道  完全没头绪
No idea. Super confused.
我觉得最好别深究
I'm finding it best to just sort of go with it.
她超级可爱的  对吧
She's super cute, though, right?
等下
Wait a minute.
哎呀呀  小旋风把粑粑拉里面了
Oh, guh! Hurricane dookied in her drawers.
哈哈  拉裤裤了
Ha-ha! Poopy pants!
她要换个新尿布
She needs a new diaper.
对  你的尿布放哪了
Right. Where do you keep your diapers?
我们没有
We don't have any.
你们居然没有
You don't... Wow.
好吧  看来我要去买点了
Okay. I guess I'll go buy some.
你已经是准妈妈了  怎么还没准备尿布呢
You're gonna be a mom and you don't have any diapers?
天啊  看好那臭孩子啊
Lord, watch over that child.
好吧
Uh, okay.
宝贝儿  阿姨抱抱
Come here, you.
刚是有人说有干酪盘吃吗
So, there's a talk of a cheese plate?
来点奶酪[笑一个]
Cheese?
国外在拍照时喜欢喊"Cheese"  相当与中国的"茄子"
谢谢
Thanks.
如果不介意的话  我想问
If you don't mind me asking...
到底出什么事吗
What-what is this all about?
你是我认识的人中最坚强  最独立
I mean, you are one of the most strong, independent,
最不可能在感恩节
non-locking-themselves-in-
把自己锁在厕所里的人
a-bathroom-on-Thanksgiving people I know.
为什么我们搬家能让你如此失控
Why-why are you so upset about us moving?
或许我比你们想象中需要你们
Maybe I just need you guys more than you think.
所以与搬家无关  你在借题发挥吗
Is this about more than us moving?
这奶酪味道不错
This is good cheese.
罗宾
Robin?
干嘛
Yeah?
你觉得我该去当捉鬼特工队员吗
Do you think I should've become a Ghostbuster?
我相信你当初的决定是对的  老兄
I think you made the right call, buddy.
泰德  我就不问巴尼从哪弄来这孩子了
Okay, Ted, I'm not gonna ask you where Barney got this baby.
可你知道他为什么这样做吗
But do you have any idea why?
前几天  我们聊到了
Well, a few nights ago, we were talking...
"女生真讨厌  咱俩要是搞基就好了"
you know, "We hate girls, we wish we were gay,"
像这样的大男人话题
just guy stuff.
然后我们当时似乎决定
And we kind of sort of decided to...
领养一个孩子
adopt a baby.
这可真疯狂
Yeah, that's crazy.
我就说嘛
I know.
-真的很疯狂吗  -确定一定以及肯定
- Is it, though? - Yes.
我就说嘛
I know.
-没有那么疯狂吧  -否认否决以及否定
- But is it, though? - Yes.
就算是疯狂又如何
Well, so what if it's crazy?
我一直在等待一个能跟我组建家庭的人
I've been ready to meet someone to start a family with
可我至今还没遇上
for a long time now, and I keep not meeting her.
巴尼是我世上最好的朋友
Barney is one of my best friends in the world,
我们很少吵架
we rarely fight,
一旦我们谈妥宠物眼镜蛇这个问题
and once we iron out the whole pet cobra thing,
我们会是绝佳老爸
we will be amazing dads.
我们为什么不能尝试一下呢
Why shouldn't we try this?
你上一次喂她是什么时候
When's the last time you fed her?
在火车上给她喝了点根汁汽水
She had some root beer on the train.
天啊  泰德  我很抱歉
Oh, Ted. And I'm sorry,
你可不能给孩子取名小旋风
but you cannot call a baby Hurricane.
其实  她的名字叫赛迪
Actually, her name is Sadie.
詹姆斯  你到这儿来干嘛
James, what are you doing here?
巴尼没告诉你们
Did Barney not tell you
我们要来过感恩节吗
that we were coming for Thanksgiving?
没有
Uh, no.
那他可能也没告诉你们
Then he probably also did not tell you
他在照看我们新领养的女儿
that he was babysitting our new daughter.
这是你的女儿吗
This is your daughter?
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
恭喜你们
And congratulations.
谢了  过来吧
Thanks. Come here.
看来得说再见了  小旋  赛迪
I guess this is good-bye, Hurri... Sadie.
你名叫小旋风  要永记心中哦
Your name is Hurricane. Don't ever forget it.
让爸爸抱
Go with him.
来吧  乖女儿
Come here. That a girl.
泰德
Hey, Ted,
我不小心听到了你那番话
I overheard your little speech.
你们没有发疯
It's not crazy.
十年之前
About ten years ago,
我和我的好友差点做了同样的事
my best friend and I nearly did the same thing.
我俩都单身  我们都想有个家
She was single, I was single, we both wanted a family.
这么做不足为奇
It made sense.
可现在呢
But now?
每天我们都感谢上天  没让我们做傻事
Every day, we thank our lucky stars that we didn't do it.
因为她和她丈夫所拥有的
'Cause what she found with her husband
我和我爱人所拥有的
and what I found with mine--
值得为之等待
it was worth the wait.
小旋风这名挺酷的
Hurricane's a cool name.
我就说嘛  汤姆
Isn't it, Tom?
宠物店离这里比较近
The pet store was closer,
我就给她买了点狗用尿不湿
so I just got her some wee-wee pads.
我还买了这个
Oh, I also got this.
这是牛肉味的  对她长牙有帮助哦[狗咬胶]
It's beef-flavored and it's good for her teeth.
詹姆斯  汤姆  你们来了
James! Tom! Hey!
莉莉
Lily...
你收到我那封关于邀请了詹姆斯和汤姆
did you get the e-mail that I sent you about inviting
来过感恩节的邮件了吗
James and Tom to Thanksgiving?
我发到你美邮网邮箱里了  你常用那个对吧
I sent it to your CompuServe. That's your main one, right?
CompuServe已于2009年关闭邮箱服务
感恩节快乐  老弟
Happy Thanksgiving, bro.
谢了
Thanks. Hi. Hey!
好吧  让你发现了
All right, you got me.
詹姆斯就是我的人贩子
James is my baby guy.
可刚才这三小时真是不可思议  对吧
But these past three hours-- magical, right?
我们能搞定的  快说我们能搞定
We can do this! Say we can do this.
我们搞不定的
We can't do this.
抱歉了  老兄
Sorry, dude.
真爱需要耐心等待
We got to wait for the real thing...
衣带渐宽终不悔
no matter how tough it gets.
为伊消得人憔悴
It gets pretty tough.
那也没办法  兄弟
I know it does, buddy.
离晚饭开始还有点时间吧
I have some time before dinner, right?
我要出去散散步
I'm going to go... I'm gonna take a little walk.
行
All right.
苍天啊
God.
我们还是朋友吧
Are we still friends?
我希望如此
Hope so.
那就好
Good.
听好了
'Cause get this.
泰德差点领养了一个孩子
Ted almost adopted a baby.
疯狂吧
Crazy, right?
可怜的家伙  日子不好过啊
Poor guy's going through some stuff.
他还想把我也拖下水
He actually tried to rope me into it.
你能想象我当爹的样子吗
Can you imagine me being someone's dad?
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.